sro.vic.gov.au 2009-12-28

# State Revenue Office Victoria - Privacy Statement (About Us)

The SRO takes its privacy obligations seriously and is committed to the responsible handling of personal information and protecting the privacy rights of individuals.

This privacy statement is made under the _Information Privacy Act 2000_, and explains our policy for handling personal information which you provide to us when you access or interact with our web site. This statement should be read in conjunction with SRO Privacy Policy and SRO Health Records Policy.

The SRO is a law enforcement agency for the purposes of the _Information Privacy Act 2000_ as an "agency responsible for the protection of public revenue under laws administered by it". As a law enforcement agency, SRO does not have to comply with some of the information privacy principles if it believes on reasonable grounds, that the non-compliance is necessary for its law enforcement functions.

## What personal information is collected via our web site?

The information we collect from you depends on how and why you access this web site. If you visit the web site to read, browse, or download information, our computer system may record information about the visit such as the number of pages visited and the duration of the visit.

Such information is only used for web site administration it is not used to identify you.

## Collection of personal information

When you e-mail us:

  * We will record your e-mail address if necessary for the provision of service to you. For example, provision of rulings, updates or notification of training sessions
  * We will only use your e-mail address for the purposes for which you provided it
  * Your e-mail address will not be added to a mailing list unless you have specifically requested this (for the purposes of receiving update materials)
  * We will not use your e-mail address for any other purpose
  * We will not disclose it without your consent
  * An unsubscribe facility is also available on subscription pages
  * Upon submitting an unsubscribe request your email address will be removed from the requested subscription.

## Other personal information collected by us, for example through the use of an online form (such as online Land Tax Clearance Certificates and eAR - electronic payroll annual reconciliations), will only:

  * Be collected by lawful and fair means
  * Be used for a lawful purpose
  * Be collected with your consent, and
  * The purpose for collection will be clear and explicit.

When you log onto the web site to use online forms, you may be required to enter a PIN (Personal Identification Number). It is your responsibility to maintain the confidentiality of your PIN, and you are responsible for all activities that occur once your PIN has been accepted by the web site

The SRO has access to electoral information held by the Victorian Electoral Commission pursuant to section 34 of the [_Electoral Act 2002_](http://www.legislation.vic.gov.au/Domino/Web_Notes/LDMS/PubStatbook.nsf/f932b66241ecf1b7ca256e92000e23be/3264bf1de203c08aca256e5b00213ffb!OpenDocument), and may use this information as specified below.

## Use and disclosure of information

The SRO only uses the personal information collected by it for the administration of its Acts-legislation to protect, manage, and collect revenue. Acts-Legislation administered by SRO have secrecy provisions that prohibit any officer of the SRO from disclosing information, unless authorised by law or with your consent. Your personal information will not be released unless the law permits it or your permission is given.

The SRO is authorised to disclose information under the secrecy provisions in Acts-legislation it administers to:-

  * The Ombudsman
  * A member of the police force
  * The Archives Authority
  * The Australian Statistician
  * Auditor General
  * The Valuer General
  * The Business Licensing Authority
  * WorkCover authority
  * Country Fire Authority
  * Roads Corporation
  * Department of Primary Industries
  * Metropolitan Fire & Emergency Services Board
  * Consumer Affairs
  * Australian Securities and Investment Commission
  * Australian Crime Commission
  * Landata
  * Interstate/Commonwealth Revenue offices
  * For the purposes of legal proceedings arising out of Acts-legislation administered by SRO
  * For the purposes of administration or execution of Acts-legislation administered by SRO, (including provision of data to outsourced providers)
  * Any other prescribed recipient
  * Other recipients with your consent

There are severe penalties for breaching these privacy and secrecy provisions, and all SRO employees are aware of their obligations under the secrecy provisions, and the _Information Privacy Act 2000_.

## Security of information

The SRO has policies and procedures in place to ensure your personal information is protected, including:

  * storage of paper based files in secure areas accessible only by authorised personnel
  * Information Systems Security Policy
  * use of computer passwords, authorised automatic password reset prompts and screen savers requiring password release to ensure that only authorised personnel have access to computer files
  * staff are authorised to access information only to the extent necessary for the performance of their duties
  * firewalls
  * use of virus protection software
  * ensuring physical security to SRO buildings to ensure access only to authorised personnel
  * Records Management Policy.

SRO provides a secure environment and a reliable system but you should be aware that there may be inherent risks associated with the transmission of information via the Internet. For those who do not wish to use the Internet, the SRO provides alternative ways of obtaining and providing information. In some circumstances, the SRO security guidelines may also require us to send particular information by non-electronic means.

## Accessing personal information

The _Information Privacy Act 2000_ gives individuals the right to access and correct personal information, and the _Health Records Act 2001_ gives individuals the right to access and correct health information (it is unlikely that SRO would hold health information unless provided by an individual).

The SRO is bound by the _Freedom on Information Act 1982_, and the primary right to information held by SRO is provided by that Act. Any request for access to personal information should be made to the Information Privacy Officer in the first instance (see below for contact details

## Contact details for information privacy officer

If you have privacy concerns please contact the Privacy Officer for the SRO, Tel: 03 9628 0556 or in writing to:-

### Privacy Officer  
(S. Polites)  
State Revenue Office  
GPO Box 1641  
Melbourne Vic 3001

## Information Privacy Principles

You can also access the information privacy principles and obtain further information from the Office of the Victorian Privacy Commissioner's web site, [www.privacy.vic.gov.au.](http://www.privacy.vic.gov.au/)

## Cookies

Cookies are data that is sent by a web site and stored in a user's computer. The cookie is recognised by the web site each time the user visits the web site. A cookie can contain data such as the parts of a web site a user has visited or the duration of the user's visit to the web site. Generally, it is recommended that users set their browser to identify the presence of cookies and to give them the option of accepting or rejecting them.

## Web Tracking

Pages on this site may be coded with Google Analytics and Omniture HBX web tracking software. This is transparent to the user, as the software makes use of an invisible code within the web page. This software may store a cookie in your browser, which contains a unique identifier, and sends information to Google Analytics and Omniture HBX. This enables the SRO to track the number of unique visitors to the site. In no way does this unique identifier identify a user personally. The SRO does not, and will not marry any data collected by Google Analytics or Omniture HBX with any personal information.

Please note:

This privacy policy does not extend beyond this web site.  When linking to other sites from this web site, we recommend that you read the privacy statement of that site to familiarise yourself with its privacy principles.

This document was last reviewed on 10/08/2009
